MICHAEL SYDNEY MOORE

Lead Front End Developer with 4+ years of commercial experience across a range of industry sectors including medical, shipping and logistics, public sector and renewable energy. Experienced in building web and mobile apps with a focus on Typescript, React and React Native in both Waterfall and Agile development environments.

SKILLS

Javascript, Typescript, Flow, HTML, CSS, React, React Native, Next.js, Preact, Three.js, Mapbox, Storybook, Redux, Webpack, Babel, Vercel, Expo, Netlify, Datadog, Sentry, Bugsnag, TDD, Unit, Jest, Enzyme, Circle Cl, Cypress

WORK EXPERIENCE

(August 2022 - Present) Browser London - Front End Lead

Shift OnWatch (Web App) - A platform that analyses key battery performance indicators and performance 24/7 for electric sea vessels

- Led the Greenfield build of the frontend using Typescript and React
- Worked with a dedicated UI and UX team to balance design and development timelines
- Worked with external and internal backend teams to build performant REST APIs
- Mentored junior members of the team in code standards and practices
- Implemented and led hiring practices and code tests for new members of the team
- Hired contractors and permanent staff
- Solved a very technically challenging UI problem that other developers said wasn't possible to achieve. Allowing a major client to deliver on their MVP promise to stakeholders

(March 2022 - August 2022) Browser London - Front End Developer

Ohealio (Web App) - A medical platform for booking consultancies and medications from gastroenterologists

- Added detailed documentation on code practices and developer experience
- Added API documentation to make refactoring more reliable
- Introduced end to end, integration and unit tests to the Next codebase
- Refactored large parts of the Next backend that was causing production errors in payment processing
- Tested, hired and managed developers in refactoring large parts of the backend
- Fixed memory leaks that were causing slow performance in production

(June 2020 - March 2022) M10C - Front End Developer

Balance (Mobile App) - A menopause and mental health app for women

- Led the complete refactoring of the front end React Native App. This included migrating the existing codebase

from Javascript to Typescript, updating class components to hooks, introducing ES6/7 syntax, and introducing

context API to reduce the amount of API requests. Overall this led to a reduction in around 5,000 lines of code and

a faster initial load time for the 500,000+ users currently using Balance

- Took the lead in converting two separate codebases into one monorepo using Webpack and React Native

- Worked with a team of backend engineers to convert all existing graphQL requests to more bespoke REST API

requests. This dramatically reduced the amount of data the client sends; improving the speed of the app for the end

user

(January 2020 - June 2020) 3DPK - Full Stack Developer (Contract)

- Developed an interactive 3D web application using three.js, enabling users to visualize and interact with complex

3D models in real-time

- Collaborated with external UI/UX designers to implement bespoke 3D models.

- Conducted comprehensive testing to ensure cross-browser compatibility and addressed performance bottlenecks

- Provided mentorship and technical guidance to junior developers, sharing best practices for three is and WebGL

development.

- Liaised with project stakeholders to gather requirements, present prototypes, and incorporate feedback into the

final product.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

SoberApp - iOS and Android dating app for people who don't drink. Built using TypeScript, React, React Native,

Expo, Mongo, Express and Node. I've also built various command line tools with Rust for automating my workflow

and managing my time at work.

EDUCATION

Art & Design - Central Saint Martins (2009)

OTHER

github: https://github.com/msmfa

email: codemoore@outlook.com

website: https://www.codemoore.com/